# W/O William Okech

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Research scientist with 10+ years of experience working in biomedical science and engineering. Strong technical skills in statistics, programming, image processing and analysis, and data visualization.

Professional interests include extracting meaningful insights from raw data and developing new biomedical technologies that can significantly impact human health.

#### **LOCATION**

Nairobi, Kenya

#### **PHONE**

Available upon request

#### **EMAIL**

willyokech@gmail.com

#### **WEBSITE**

www.williamokech.com

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- R and RStudio (4 years)
- MATLAB (4 years)
- Python (2 years)
- CellProfiler (3 years)
- Fiji / ImageJ (10 years)

# PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Biomedical Engineering Society
- Certified Carpentries Instructor (Data and Software)

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Scientific Editor, Charlesworth Author Services	2020-Present
Reviewer, Biomedicine and Pharmacotherapy	2019–Present
Postdoctoral Research Associate, University of Pittsburgh	2017–2019
Postdoctoral Research Fellow, Johns Hopkins University	2016–2017
Postdoctoral Research Associate, University of Rochester	2015–2016
Graduate Research Assistant, University of Rochester	2010–2015
Graduate Teaching Assistant, University of Rochester	2011–2012
Graduate Research Assistant, University of Oxford	2010
<b>Undergraduate Research Assistant,</b> University of Pennsylvania	2007–2008

#### **EDUCATION**

Ph.D. Biomedical Engineering, University of Rochester	October 2015
M.S. Biomedical Engineering, University of Rochester	May 2012
MSc Biomedical Engineering, University of Oxford	September 2010
B.S.E. Bioengineering, University of Pennsylvania	May 2008

## HONORS, AWARDS, AND SERVICE

- Judge for the International Genetically Engineered Machines (iGEM)
   Competition; 2021–2022
- Judge for the LATAM International Genetically Engineered Machines (iGEM)
   Design League Competition; 2021
- Grand Award Judge for the Intel International Science and Engineering Fair, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania; 2018
- Computational modeling "Finding Your Inner Modeler" Travel Award (National Science Foundation; 2017 & 2018)
- Bioengineering Senior Design Award (University of Pennsylvania; 2008)
- Dean's List (University of Pennsylvania; 2007–2008)

Е				

Available upon request